A Finding Aid to the Anton Refregier Papers, circa 1900-circa 1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.refranto
Archives of American Art
Anton Refregier papers
circa 1900-circa 1990
AAA.refranto
Archives of American Art
35.5 Linear feet
The papers of Woodstock area painter, muralist, and designer, Anton Refregier (1905-1979) date from circa 1900 to circa 1990 and measure 35.5 linear feet. The collection records Refregier's early commercial work and murals for the Works Progress Adminstration (WPA) and documents his career through to the 1970s with records of commissions for many public and private buildings, exhibitions in the United States and abroad, teaching positions, essays and publications, and extensive travel, particularly to the Soviet Union and Mexico. The collection contains scattered biographical material, personal and business correspondence, notes and writings, 15 diaries and journals, mural and tapestry files, exhibition files, personal business records, printed material, 10 scrapbooks, artwork including sketches and cartoons for murals, and photographs of Refregier, his friends, family and travels.
Refregier, Anton
Provenance
Donated 1983 by Lila Refregier, widow of Anton Refregier, and in 1992 by Brigit R. Sutton, Refregier's daughter.
Related Material
Also found in the Archives of American Art are an oral history interview with Anton Refregier, 1964, Nov. 5 by Joseph Trovato; and Papers regarding Anton Refregier mural controversy, 1953.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Russian-born Woodstock painter Anton Refregier (1905-1979) immigrated to the United States in 1920. Refregier was well-known for his sometimes controversial social realist murals for the WPA.
After an apprenticeship to the sculptor, Vasilief, in Paris, Anton Refregier attended the Rhode Island School of Design from 1920-1925 and studied with Hans Hoffman in Germany in 1927. He had his first one-man show at ACA Galleries in New York City in 1942 and settled in Woodstock, New York, with his wife, Lila, and three children Anton, Jr., Brigit and Aleksandre, where he became a prominent member of the artist community.
Refregier completed several social realist murals for the federal Works Progress Adminstration (WPA) program, including one at the New York Worlds Fair in 1939 and the controversial Rincon Annex Post Office mural in San Francisco begun in 1941. He also completed interior design installations for businesses such as the nightclub, Cafe Society Uptown, and the restaurant, The Cookery, in New York City. In addition to being an easel and mural painter Refregier worked in tapestry, mosaic, ceramic, and collage, and completed many commissions for hotels, banks, hospitals, restaurants, synagogues, supermarkets and deparment stores throughout the country.
Refregier taught at various institutions including Stanford University, the University of Arkansas, and Bard College and his publications inlcude Natural Figure Drawing (1948), An Artist's Journey (1965), and Sketches of the Soviet Union (1978). He traveled regularly to the Soviet Union to explore and exchange ideas about art and culture and as a representative of the World Peace Council.
Anton Refregier died in Moscow in October 1979 while visiting the Soviet Union. His work can be found in many museums including the Corcoran Gallery of Art, the Metropolitan Museum, the San Francisco Museum of Art, and the Whitney Museum of American Art.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Woodstock area painter, muralist, and designer, Anton Refregier (1905-1979) date from circa 1900 to circa 1990 and measure 35.5 linear feet. The collection records Refregier's early commercial work and murals for the Works Progress Adminstration (WPA) and documents his career through to the 1970s with records of commissions for many public and private buildings, exhibitions in the United States and abroad, teaching positions, essays and publications, and extensive travel, particularly to the Soviet Union and Mexico. The collection contains scattered biographical material, personal and business correspondence, notes and writings, diaries and journals, mural and tapestry files, exhibition files, personal business records, printed material, scrapbooks, artwork including sketches and cartoons for murals, and photographs of Refregier, his friends, family and travels.
Biographical material contains legal records such as Refregier's will and marriage and death records, passports, resume material and 2 interview transcripts.
Correspondence, both chronological and alphabetical, constitutes almost a third of the collection and documents all aspects of Refregier's career including his work for the WPA, private commissions, representation by ACA Galleries, his involvement with groups such as the Woodstock Artists Association and his teaching work for institutions such as Bard College. Also documented are his involvement with local political groups and international organizations such as the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship and the World Peace Council, and travels including visits to the Soviet Union. Notable correspondents include Henry Dreyfuss, Philip Evergood, Rockwell Kent, Emmy-Lou Packard, and Byron Randall. Correspondence also includes family letters written primarily by Refregier to Lila Refregier, in addition to greeting cards received by the Refregier family, many of which contain original arwork.
Writings are primarily by Refregier and include drafts of many essays and autobiographical writings, in addition to copies of published works including Natural Figure Drawing, An Artists Journey and Sketches of the Soviet Union.
The collection contains diaries and journals from 12 years in various formats including published and handmade day planners and typed and handwritten journal entries. They include sketches and primarily record travel and daily activities including specific projects such as the New York World's Fair mural (1938-1939).
Mural and Tapestry files document individual commissions bid on and/or completed by Refregier. The creation of the Rincon Annex Post Office mural and subsequent controversies over its subject matter are well-documented here, as are many of Refregier's commissions for banks, hospitals, hotels, shopping centers, and schools.
Exhibition files document at least 15 of Refregier's exhibitions, including his first one-man show at ACA Galleries (1942) and his exhibition of paintings at the Hermitage Museum (1967) in what was then Leningrad.
Personal business records contain addresses of contacts. Scattered records referencing market values for Refregier's work can be found throughout the series in records such as bills and receipts, financial notes and tax records.
Printed material provides extensive coverage of Refregier's entire career through announcements, invitations, catalogs, and news clippings. His interests in art, literature, music, theater and politics are also well-represented in these files.
The collection contains 10 scrapbooks, mostly in fragmented condition, which contain a mixture of photographs, sketches and other artwork, notes and fragments of writings, and printed material. The scrapbooks document a variety of subjects including Refregier's family life, travels to Guatemala and the Soviet Union, and the artist at work.
Artwork consists primarily of artwork by Refregier in the form of mural design sketches and cartoons in various media, including pencil, ink and pastel, in addition to 21 sketchbooks, many of which also contain journal entries and notes. Also found here are prints and reproductions of Refregier's "Peace card" block engravings for every year from 1950-1973, with the exception of 1970.
Photographs document all phases of Refregier's career and include family photographs dating from circa 1900, photos of Refregier in the studio including work for the WPA, Refregier and other artists and individuals at events and parties from the 1940s-1970s, travel snapshots probably taken in Chile, Guatemala, Mexico, and the Soviet Union, and photographs of artwork and installations. Individuals pictured include Julio de Diego, Marion Greenwood, Rockwell Kent, Pablo O'Higgins and David Siqueiros; also, a series of press photographs by Albert A. Freeman pictures Refregier with Howard Fast, Norman Bel Geddes, Marion Greenwood, John Kingsbury, Yasuo Kuniyoshi and Harry Stockwell. One photograph by Eliot Elisofon, 2 by Eugene Morley and 4 by Max Yavno can also be found here.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1925-1980 (Box 1; 0.25 linear ft.)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1912-circa 1990s (Boxes 1-11, 36, OVs 38, 45; 10.4 linear ft.)
Series 3: Writings, circa 1930s-circa 1970s (Boxes 11-14, OV 45; 3.3 linear ft.)
Series 4: Diaries and Journals, 1923-1979 (Box 15; 0.6 linear ft.)
Series 5: Mural and Tapestry Files, circa 1930s-circa 1970s (Boxes 15-18, 36, OVs 38, 45, 46, RD 42; 3.75 linear ft.)
Series 6: Exhibition Files, 1942-1981 (Boxes 18-19; 0.6 linear ft.)
Series 7: Personal Business Records, 1920s-1980s (Boxes 19-20; 1.8 linear ft.)
Series 8: Printed Material, circa 1920s-1980s (Boxes 21-28, 36; 7.4 linear ft.)
Series 9: Scrapbooks, 1930s-1960s (Boxes 28, 37; 0.6 linear ft.)
Series 10: Artwork, circa 1930s-circa 1970s (Boxes 28-30, 36, OVs 40, 41, RDs 42-44; 2.3 linear ft.)
Series 11: Photographic Material, ca. 1900-1980s (Boxes 31-35, 39; 4.5 linear ft.)
ACA Galleries.; Bard College. -- Faculty; De Diego, Julio, 1900-; Dreyfuss, Henry, 1904-; Elisofon, Eliot; Evergood, Philip, 1901-1973; Fast, Howard, 1914-; Geddes, Norman Bel, 1893-1958; Gosudarstvennyĭ Ėrmitazh. (Russia); Greenwood, Marion, 1909-1970; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971; Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1889-1953; Morley, Eugene, 1909-1953; National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (U.S.); New York World's Fair (1939-1940).; O'Higgins, Pablo, 1904-; Packard, Emmy Lou, 1914-; Randall, Byron, 1918-1999; Refregier, Lila; Siqueiros, David Alfaro; United States. Works Progress Administration.; Woodstock Artists Association (Woodstock, N.Y.); World Peace Council; Yavno, Max; Art--Commissioning; Art--Study and teaching; Artists' studios--Photographs; Cartoons (working drawings); Chile; Designers--New York (State); Diaries; Greeting cards; Guatemala; Interviews; Mexico; Mural painting and decoration--Archival resources--20th century; Muralists--New York--Woodstock; Painters--New York (State)--Woodstock; Photographs; Political clubs; Scrapbooks; Sketches; Soviet Union; Tapestry; Transcripts; Travel journals
- Biographical Material, 1925-1980; Series 1; 0.25 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes Refregier's marriage, naturalization and death certificates, passports and other travel documentation, wills, interview transcripts, membership cards and awards, and resume material.
  - Awards, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Graduation Program (copy), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Identification and Membership Cards, 1930s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Interview of Refregier, Transcript, by Kleinholz, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Interview material from Lois Spenkin, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Interview of Refregier, Transcript, by Joseph Trovato, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Last Wills and Testaments, Anton and Lila Refregier, 1975, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Marriage and Naturalization Certificates, 1930, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Medical Records and Death Certificate (copy), 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Passports and Travel Documents, circa 1960s-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Refregier, Lila, High School Diploma, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Refregier, Valentina, Naturalization Certificate and Expenses Related to her Death, 1926, 1967, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Resume Material, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Who's Who, circa 1950s-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1912-circa 1990s; Series 2; 10.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-11, 36, OVs 38, 45
  This series provides extensive documentation of Refregier's personal and professional life through correspondence in addition to notes, financial and legal records, printed material and some photographs and sketches. It includes family correspondence consisting primarily of letters written by Refregier while traveling and working in Mexico, San Francisco (on the Rincon Annex Post Office mural) and the Soviet Union. Chronological and alphabetical correspondence contains correspondence with artists including Henry Dreyfuss, Philip Evergood, Rockwell Kent, Emmy Lou Packard, and Byron Randall, colleagues who worked with Refregier on murals and tapestries such as Walter and Bundy Illsley, WPA administrators, galleries and museums, public and corporate business clients, and national and international political organizations in which Refreigier was extensively involved, such as the World Peace Council. The series also documents Refregier's participation in artist organizaitons such as the Woodstock Artists Association and his teaching work for institutions such as Bard College, where he was professor of painting from 1962-1964.
  Files relating to the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship contain correspondence with Rockwell Kent who was involved extensively with this organization and with the World Peace Council.
  Researchers should note that chronological correspondence in Series 2.2. supplements documentation of subjects found in the alphabetical files of Series 2.3. Correspondence files relating to mural and tapestry commissions should also be used in conjunction with Series 5: Murals and Tapestry Files where more detailed information about certain commissions can be found.
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged as 4 subseries:
  2.1: Family Correspondence, 1940s-1970s
  2.2: Chronological Correspondence, 1912-circa 1990s
  2.3: Alphabetical Correspondence, 1930s-1982
  2.4: Greeting Cards, circa 1940s-circa 1970s
  - Family Correspondence, 1940s-1970s; 2.1
    - Refregier, Anton and Lila, 1940s-1970s; (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 15-20)
    - Refregier, Aleksandre, Anton, Brigit and Lila, 1950s-1970s; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
    - Refregier, Anton, Lila and Anton Jr. (Toto), circa 1940s-circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1912-circa 1990s; 2.2
    - Correspondence, circa 1920s-circa 1970s; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 24-26)
    - Correspondence, 1912-1940; (13 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-39)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1956; (30 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-30)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1964; (26 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-26)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1969; (25 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-25)
    - Correspondence, circa 1970s-1980; (27 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-27)
    - Correspondence, 1980s-1990s; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Alphabetical Correspondence, 1930s-1982; 2.3
    Records are arranged alphabetically by name or subject.
    - ACA Galleries, circa 1940s-1968; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
    - ACA Galleries, Print Group Notes, circa 1950s (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Aguilar, Jose Sanches, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - American Dialogue Article on Refregier, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - American Soviet Chamber of Commerce (Rosenfeld, Herbert T.), 1945, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - An Artist's Journey, Publication of Limited Edition, 1946, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Anti-War Protest, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Archives of American Art, 1964, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Art Commission, City of San Francisco, Reception, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Artist Associations, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Artists Equity Association, 1950s-1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Arts in the Theatre Institute, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Associated American Artists Galleries, 1952-1954, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Oversized material housed in OV 45
    - Associated American Artists Galleries Fabrics, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Associations and Organizations, Correspondence with, 1950s-1966 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Bard College, 1960s; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
    - Brandeis University Book, 1953-1955 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Buchenwald" Story, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - "Chamber of Horrors" Life under the Nazis Committee, circa 1937 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Collection of Letters from "Friends and People in General,", 1949-1971 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Collector's Guild Ltd. and A. Lublin, Inc., 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System Television, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      (includes artwork for "Out of the Darkness")
    - Columbia Pictures, Artwork for "The Last Ten Days,", 1956 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Commercial Decal, Inc., 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Committee to Abolish the House Un-American Activities Committee, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Condolence Letters on Death of Alek Refregier, 1971-1972; (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 34-37)
    - Contacts, Architecture, circa 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Contacts, Florida, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Cookery Lafayette, Inc., 1955-1970; (3 folders; oversized material housed in OV 38) (Box 6, Folder 40-42)
    - Covington Fabrics, 1955-1956; (Oversized material housed in OV 38) (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - D Contemporary Paintings, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Davis, Angela, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Donations of Artwork, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - East River Gallery Agreements, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Elizabeth Art Club, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Erikssen, Adelyne, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Evergood, Phil, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Everhart Museum, Scranton, PA, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Faulkner, Stanley, 1961-1962, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Federal Arts Committee, 1937-1938; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
    - Film Artists, Inc., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Fine Arts 260 (Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc.), 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - First Unitarian Church, Los Angeles, CA, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Garelick's Gallery, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Get Well Cards/Letters, 1970; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
    - Give All Thy Terrors to the Wind, Drawing, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Glass Panels, Chandler Cudlipp Associates, Inc., 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Government Sponsorship of the Arts,", 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Harbor Gallery, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Heritage Gallery, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Illsley, Walter and Bundy, 1968-1972 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Illustration, "Steel and Metal Workers-It Takes a Fight to Win," Pamphlet by Gus Hall, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Illustrations, Vanguard Records, circa 1959-1961; (Oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Inquiries to and from Refregier about Jobs, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - International Publishers, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - James Seeman Studios Inc., 1957-1964 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Japan Council Against the A and H Bombs, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - John Reed Club and American Artists Congress, 1930s; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 24-25)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship Application, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Kent, Rockwell, Testimonial Dinner, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Lecture Program, circa 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Lectures, 1958-1966 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Lectures (Box 7)
      - "Art and Artists in the Soviet Union,", 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - "Art and Artists in the Soviet Union," California, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Miami, FL, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - New York State Art Teachers Association, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Philadelphia Social Science Forum, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - "The Creative Environment,", 1960 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Madison Square Gardens Paegant, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Mainstream, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Marble Arch Gallery, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Morris Lapidus. Harle & Liebman, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Mosman, Warren T., 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Muldavin, Joe, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Murals, Inc., 1952-1956 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - N. W. Ayer & Son, Inc., 1955-1957, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Nation, Illustrations for, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, circa 1960s (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1940s-1975; (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 47-50)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Exhibition (1960), 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Public Statements, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - National Council of Jewish Women, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - National Guardian Calendar, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Natural Figure Drawing, 1946-1947, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Natural Figure Drawing, Photographic Material, 1946-1947; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 57-58)
    - New World Review, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - New York Shipbuilding Corporation, 1950-1959; (Oversized material housed in OV 38) (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - New York State Council on the Arts Grant, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Paintings Sold, 1958-1964 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Park East Hospital, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pending Jobs, 1955-1965; (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1957, 1963-1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Personal Correspondence, Lila Refregier, 1960-1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Political Correspondence, 1950s-1970s; (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
    - Possible Commissions, 1961-1973; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - Postcards, Blank, circa 1920s-circa 1970s; (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 14-17)
    - Poster, International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Posters, 1967-1968, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
    - Print Commissions-Fine Art Promotions (Henrietta Lippman), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1952-1978; (5 folders) (Box 8, Folder 22-26)
    - Professional Correspondence re: Pictures in Fortune Magazine, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Progress Publishers, Moscow, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Projects, Miscellaneous, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Public Art Preservation Committee, circa 1950s-circa 1970 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Public/Political Statements, 1950s, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Publication, An Artists Journey, 1962-1966; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 33-34)
    - Publication, An Artists Journey, International Promotion, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Publishers Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Puerto Rico, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Red Book Magazine, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Refregier, Alek, World Festival of Youth, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Research on New Deal Art Projects, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Roberson Memorial Center, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Roberts, Holland, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Rosenberg Case, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Sales, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Sales, Prints, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Sanity, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Schools for Alek Refregier, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Sheraton International Golf Club, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Siqueiros, David Alfaro, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - "Sketches of the Soviet Union,", 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - "Song of Peace,", 1959 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Southern Conference Educational Fund, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 52)